gearjunkie.com 2018-12-31

# Privacy Policy | GearJunkie

This privacy policy sets out how GearJunkie uses and protects any information that you give while using the GearJunkie website.

Should we ask you to provide certain information by which you can be identified when using this website, then you can be assured that it will only be used in accordance with this privacy statement.

GearJunkie may change this policy from time to time by updating this page. You should check this page regularly to ensure that you are happy with any changes. This policy is effective from May 25, 2018.

#### What We Collect

We may collect the following information voluntarily as part of participation in contests, surveys, email subscriptions, and other activities:

  * Contact information including email address.
  * Demographic information such as postcode, preferences, and interests.
  * Other information relevant to customer surveys and/or offers.

#### What We Do With The Information We Gather

We require this information to understand your needs and provide you with a better service, and in particular for the following reasons:

  * We may use the information to improve our products and services.
  * We may periodically send promotional emails 

about new products, special offers, or other information that we think you may find interesting using the email address which you have provided.

#### Security

We are committed to ensuring that your information is secure. In order to prevent unauthorized access or disclosure, we have put in place suitable physical, electronic, and managerial procedures to safeguard and secure the information we collect online. We use industry-standard SSL encryption to protect data-in-transit. Any user data that we collect and store is in a secure database with effective electronic controls and managerial processes to prevent unauthorized access and distribution.

#### How We Use Cookies

Gearjunkie.com sets several cookies which are necessary for the proper functioning of the web site. Additionally, our advertising platform and providers set and read cookies to track the advertisements our visitors see. This data is not personally identifiable.

A cookie is a small file which asks permission to be placed on your computer’s hard drive. Once you agree, the file is added and the cookie helps analyze web traffic or lets you know when you visit a particular site. Cookies allow web applications to respond to you as an individual. The web application can tailor its operations to your needs, likes, and dislikes by gathering and remembering information about your preferences.

We use traffic log cookies to identify which pages are being used. This helps us analyze data about web page traffic and improve our website in order to tailor it to customer needs. We only use this information for statistical analysis purposes and then the data is removed from the system.

Overall, cookies help us provide you with a better website, by enabling us to monitor which pages you find useful and which you do not. A cookie in no way gives us access to your computer or any information about you, other than the data you choose to share with us.

You can choose to accept or decline cookies. Most web browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies if you prefer. This may prevent you from taking full advantage of the website.

#### Affiliate Link Disclosure Statement

We work hard to test gear and find outdoor stories that are relevant to you. Did you know that you can support GearJunkie by purchasing your gear through the links on our site? Yup, it’s true, and we appreciate the support as it helps us provide top-notch stories and gear reviews to you and millions of other readers. 

In some of our stories, we link to relevant and trusted affiliate partners like REI, Amazon, Patagonia, The North Face, etc. If a GearJunkie user clicks an affiliate link and purchases a product or service from any of these affiliate sites within a set amount of time GearJunkie receives a small commission. Affiliate linking has become a regular process in digital publishing. Though these commissions help us pay for things like excellent journalism, rent, and office beers, it doesn’t interfere with our goal of giving objective, unbiased gear reviews and stories. Our editorial and marketing teams are separate divisions within GearJunkie and we do not accept payment in any form for positive reviews or stories. 

#### Advertising

Some of our advertisers occasionally serve you cookies as well. We do not have control over cookies placed by advertisers. We may use advertising service vendors to help present advertisements on the website, one of which is https://www.google.com/adsense. These vendors may use cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies to serve you advertisements tailored to interests you have shown by browsing on this and other sites you have visited, to determine whether you have seen a particular advertisement before and to avoid sending you duplicate advertisements. In doing so, these vendors may collect non-personal data such as your browser type, your operating system, Web pages visited, time of visits, content viewed, ads viewed, and other clickstream data. The use of cookies, web beacons, or similar technologies by these advertising service vendors is subject to their own privacy policies, not ours, and Service Provider disclaims all liability in connection therewith.

#### Links To Other Websites

Our website may contain links to other websites of interest. However, once you have used these links to leave our site, you should note that we do not have any control over that other website. Therefore, we cannot be responsible for the protection and privacy of any information which you provide whilst visiting such sites and such sites are not governed by this privacy statement. You should exercise caution and look at the privacy statement applicable to the website in question.

#### Controlling Your Personal Information

If you have previously agreed to allowing us using your personal information for direct marketing purposes, you may change your mind at any time by contacting us.

We will not sell, distribute, or lease your personal information to third parties unless we have your permission or are required by law to do so. We may use your personal information to send you promotional information about third parties which we think you may find interesting if you tell us that you wish this to happen.

#### Opt Out

If you believe that any information we are holding on you is incorrect or incomplete, please contact us.

#### Product Review Policy

Want to know how we get products to review and what we do with them? Take a look at our product review policy.
